Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
And today we're talking about a very important day in a couple's life.
今天我们聊的是一对情侣生活中非常重要的一天。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to a wedding.
我们要去参加一场婚礼。
But this time, it's not going to be so romantic because actually the groom is having second
但这次，可不会那么浪漫，因为实际上新郎正在犹豫
thoughts about the wedding.
要不要结婚。
Okay, that means he's nervous and he's not positive he wants to get married today.
好的，意思是他很紧张，不确定今天想不想结婚。
So remember the groom is the man, the bride is the woman.
所以记住，新郎是男人，新娘是女人。
Let's jump right into this dialogue.
我们直接进入对话吧。
Listen to what's going on and when we come back, we'll be talking about some of the words
听听发生了什么，等我们回来时，会讨论一些你听到的单词
and phrases you've heard.
和短语。
Man, I'm freaking out.
天哪，我快吓死了。
You gotta help me.
你得帮帮我。
Whoa, whoa, take it easy.
哇，哇，别紧张。
Relax.
放松点。
Jeez, you're sweating like a pig.
天啊，你汗流浃背的。
What's going on?
怎么了？
I can't go through with this.
我做不到。
I just can't.
我真的不行。
I'm not ready for marriage.
我还没准备好结婚。
What was I thinking?
我当时在想什么？
I'm only 35 years old.
我才35岁。
I've got my entire life ahead of me.
我的人生还长着呢。
Adventure's waiting.
冒险在等着我。
I can't settle down yet.
我还不能安定下来。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
It wasn't more than a month ago that you were rambling on about how you are tired of living
不到一个月前，你还喋喋不休地说你厌倦了
the life of a bachelor and how you envy your friends that have a family.
单身生活，还羡慕那些有家庭的朋友。
I know, I know.
我知道，我知道。
Let's think this through.
我们好好想想。
First of all, you cannot leave Amy at the altar.
首先，你不能把Amy丢在圣坛上。
Not only will she be humiliated and kill you, but she is the woman that you love and the
她不仅会感到羞辱然后杀了你，而且她是你爱的女人，
woman of your dreams.
是你梦中的女人。
Why would you want to end that or jeopardize it like this?
你为什么要这样结束或危及这一切？
Second of all, you are just getting cold feet.
其次，你只是临阵退缩了。
You know deep down inside that you want to marry her.
你内心深处知道你想娶她。
So cut the crap and do it.
所以别废话了，去做吧。
You're right.
你说得对。
I'm being crazy.
我真是疯了。
Okay, I'm ready.
好了，我准备好了。
Let's do this.
我们开始吧。
Great.
太好了。
Phew, that was a close one.
呼，好险啊。
You had me going there for a minute.
你刚才真让我捏了一把汗。
I thought I was going to have to slap some sense into you.
我还以为我得打醒你呢。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So almost, he almost didn't get married, but luckily you have a good friend to help you
所以差一点，他差点没结婚，但幸好有个好朋友帮他
out.
解决了问题。
Exactly.
没错。
So this friend really saved the day, made sure that the groom didn't get too nervous
所以这个朋友真的救了场，确保新郎不会太紧张，
and had some really positive words.
还说了一些非常积极的话。
So let's take a listen to some of these marriage words in today's Language Takeaway.
那我们来听听今天“语言要点”中一些关于婚姻的词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright, so as you mentioned, we have this word marriage.
好的，正如你提到的，我们有“marriage”这个词。
Now marriage is the noun form, right, of actually getting married or to be married.
“Marriage”是名词形式，对吧，指的是结婚或已婚的状态。
Right.
对。
Marriage is the noun, the word that describes the relationship between two married people.
“Marriage”是名词，描述两个已婚人士之间关系的词。
Okay, and so you have a relationship, maybe you're dating, but once you get married, the
好的，所以你们有关系，可能是在约会，但一旦结婚，
thing between you as a man and a woman, that's your marriage.
你们之间作为男人和女人的东西，就是你们的婚姻。
Your marriage.
你们的婚姻。
You could say our marriage is in danger.
你可以说我们的婚姻有危险。
We need to work on our marriage.
我们需要经营我们的婚姻。
Exactly.
没错。
It's a happy marriage.
这是一段幸福的婚姻。
Alright.
好的。
Okay, so that's marriage.
好了，那就是“marriage”。
Now if you get married, and this guy, he mentioned a phrase which was to settle down.
现在如果你结婚了，这个家伙提到一个短语是“settle down”。
To settle down.
安定下来。
This is a very important phrase.
这是一个非常重要的短语。
To settle down means to get serious, mature, and to stop living like a child.
“Settle down”意思是变得认真、成熟，不再像孩子一样生活。
It means really to have a house or to start having kids.
它真正意味着拥有房子或开始生孩子。
It's a time in life.
这是人生中的一个阶段。
So to settle down is to become more stable, right?
所以“settle down”是变得更稳定，对吧？
As you say, to buy a house, to have a family, to stay in one place and not be so adventurous
就像你说的，买房子、组建家庭、待在一个地方，不再那么冒险
or stuff like that.
之类的。
Exactly.
没错。
So it's to calm down and to be more fixed in life.
所以是冷静下来，在生活中更固定。
Alright.
好的。
Now the opposite of this would be to be a bachelor.
现在它的反义词是“bachelor”。
Right.
对。
So bachelor is a single man, someone who's not married.
所以“bachelor”是单身男人，没结婚的人。
And you often hear this term when we talk about apartments.
你经常在谈论公寓时听到这个词。
So bachelor pad is an apartment that's specific to a single man.
所以“bachelor pad”是专属于单身男人的公寓。
Usually there's lots of video games and a fancy TV and a pool table.
通常有很多电子游戏、一台花哨的电视和一张台球桌。
Exactly.
没错。
Alright.
好的。
So bachelor.
所以“bachelor”。
We had a lesson about this called bachelor party.
我们有一课是关于这个的，叫“bachelor party”。
Right.
对。
Which is a party for a man right before he gets married.
那是男人结婚前举办的派对。
And bachelor is a special word for a man who's not yet married.
“Bachelor”是专门指还没结婚的男人的词。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And now as they were talking about not getting married, he said that you can't leave Amy
现在当他们谈论不结婚时，他说你不能把Amy
at the altar.
丢在圣坛上。
So you often hear this in movies.
所以你经常在电影里听到这个。
She got left at the altar or you can't leave her at the altar.
她被丢在圣坛上了，或者你不能把她丢在圣坛上。
This word altar is actually religious.
“Altar”这个词实际上是宗教性的。
Altar is the table in a church where the priest does all of his work.
“Altar”是教堂里牧师做所有工作的桌子。
Right.
对。
Alright.
好的。
So an altar is a special religious table.
所以“altar”是一张特殊的宗教桌子。
So usually two people will stand in front of an altar and get married right with the
所以通常两个人会站在圣坛前结婚，牧师
priest who is doing his thing there.
在那里做他的事。
Exactly.
没错。
He says, do you Joe take Samantha to be your bride?
他说，你Joe愿意娶Samantha为妻吗？
Blah, blah, blah.
等等等等。
So that happens at a special place called the altar.
所以那发生在一个叫圣坛的特殊地方。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And not at the normal mass like on Sundays.
而不是像周日那样的普通弥撒。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
And for the last word or phrase today, it's to get cold feet.
今天最后一个单词或短语是“get cold feet”。
You're just getting cold feet.
你只是临阵退缩了。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a very funny phrase in English because it doesn't actually mean that your
这在英语中是一个非常有趣的短语，因为它实际上不是指你的
cold feet are cold.
脚冷。
Right.
没错。
So cold feet means you're nervous about something.
所以“cold feet”意思是你在某件事上感到紧张。
You might change your mind.
你可能会改变主意。
Okay.
好的。
So people often talk about men and women getting cold feet before a wedding.
所以人们经常说男人和女人在婚礼前临阵退缩。
But you can also relate it to any other situation, not only getting married.
但也可以用在其他任何情况，不只是结婚。
Right.
没错。
Yeah.
是的。
For example, I'm going to go jump out of an airplane tomorrow.
比如，我明天要去跳伞。
Okay.
好的。
Fast forward tomorrow.
快进到明天。
Oh no, I have cold feet.
哦不，我临阵退缩了。
I don't think I want to jump out of an airplane.
我觉得我不想跳伞了。
Okay.
好的。
So that's to get cold feet.
这就是“get cold feet”。
To have second thoughts or doubts about actually doing something.
对实际要做的事情产生犹豫或怀疑。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Cold feet.
临阵退缩。
Alright.
好了。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue again.
那我们再听一遍对话吧。
Let's keep a lookout for all of these words and we'll be back in a little bit.
留意这些词语，我们一会儿回来。
Man, I'm freaking out.
天啊，我吓坏了。
You got to help me.
你得帮帮我。
Whoa, whoa.
哇，哇。
Take it easy.
别紧张。
Relax.
放松点。
Jeez, you're sweating like a pig.
天哪，你汗流浃背。
What's going on?
怎么了？
I can't go through with this.
我做不到这件事。
I just can't.
我就是做不到。
I'm not ready for marriage.
我还没准备好结婚。
What was I thinking?
我当时在想什么？
I'm only 35 years old.
我才35岁。
I've got my entire life ahead of me.
我的人生还长着呢。
Adventure's waiting.
冒险在等着我。
I can't settle down yet.
我还不能安定下来。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
It wasn't more than a month ago that you were rambling on about how you are tired of living
不到一个月前，你还喋喋不休地说你厌倦了
the life of a bachelor and how you envy your friends that have a family.
单身生活，还羡慕那些有家庭的朋友。
I know.
我知道。
Let's think this through.
我们好好想想。
First of all, you cannot leave Amy at the altar.
首先，你不能把艾米丢在婚礼上。
Not only will she be humiliated and kill you, but she is the woman that you love and the
她不仅会感到羞辱并杀了你，而且她是你爱的女人，
woman of your dreams.
是你梦中的女人。
Why would you want to end that or jeopardize it like this?
你为什么要这样结束或危及这一切？
Second of all, you are just getting cold feet.
其次，你只是临阵退缩了。
You know deep down inside that you'd want to marry her.
你内心深处知道你想娶她。
So cut the crap and do it.
所以别废话了，去做吧。
You're right.
你说得对。
I'm being crazy.
我疯了。
Okay.
好的。
I'm ready.
我准备好了。
Let's do this.
我们开始吧。
Great.
太好了。
Phew.
呼。
That was a close one.
好险啊。
You had me going there for a minute.
你刚才可把我吓到了。
I thought I was going to have to slap some sense into you.
我还以为我得打醒你呢。
All right.
好了。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now why don't we take a look at four key phrases that we found in this dialogue on
现在让我们看看在“流利度构建”部分
Fluency Builder.
从这个对话中找到的四个关键短语。
流利度构建。
This first one is a really great phrase because it's very, well, it's easy to picture this
第一个短语真的很棒，因为它很容易让人想象出
what we're describing.
我们描述的画面。
To sweat like a pig.
汗流浃背。
Okay.
好的。
You're sweating like a pig.
你汗流浃背。
All right.
好了。
This is a way to say that someone is sweating a lot.
这是一种说某人流了很多汗的方式。
A lot.
很多。
Okay.
好的。
And it's really gross or disgusting.
而且很恶心或令人反感。
Now do pigs actually sweat?
猪真的会出汗吗？
I don't know if pigs actually sweat but you imagine someone smells bad and they have sweat
我不知道猪是否真的出汗，但你可以想象某人身上有汗味，
on their face and their back and their arms.
脸上、背上和胳膊上都是汗。
All right.
好了。
Well, sometimes don't you say you're sweating like a dog?
嗯，有时候你不是会说“汗如雨下”吗？
You could also say that.
你也可以那么说。
I guess we like animals in English but this is just a really great way to say that someone
我想英语里喜欢用动物比喻，但这只是形容某人
is really sweaty.
汗流浃背的一个很棒的方式。
All right.
好了。
And well, he was sweating and he was really nervous because he said, I can't go through
他当时在流汗，而且非常紧张，因为他说：“我做不到
with this.
这件事。”
What does he mean go through with this?
他说的“go through with this”是什么意思？
With what?
什么事？
To go through with means to actually do something.
“Go through with”意思是实际去做某事。
Okay.
好的。
So maybe I say, I don't want to jump out of an airplane.
所以也许我说：“我不想跳伞。”
I can't go through with this.
“我做不到这件事。”
Okay.
好的。
I can't jump.
“我跳不了。”
So it depends on what we're actually talking about.
所以这取决于我们实际在谈论什么。
If we're talking about a wedding, you say, I can't go through with this.
如果我们在谈论婚礼，你会说：“我做不到这件事。”
I can't get married.
“我结不了婚。”
So if you're planning a robbery, you say, well, in the last minute, I couldn't go through
所以如果你在策划抢劫，你会说：“嗯，在最后一刻，
with it.
我下不了手。”
I backed out.
我退出了。
I can't complete what I talked about doing.
我无法完成我计划要做的事。
Okay.
好的。
And now the friend, he finally gets kind of angry and he says, cut the crap.
现在朋友终于有点生气了，他说：“别废话了。”
Oh man, this is a very common phrase.
哦，天啊，这是一个很常见的短语。
All right.
好了。
This is someone says this if they don't want to listen to you complain anymore.
如果有人不想再听你抱怨，就会这么说。
Okay.
好的。
Marco, cut the crap.
马可，别废话了。
Okay.
好的。
I don't want to hear your excuses.
我不想听你的借口。
I don't want to hear your complaints.
我不想听你的抱怨。
I want to just hear solutions, solutions, ideas, positive things.
我只想听解决方案、想法、积极的东西。
So to cut the crap is no more complaints, no more excuses or no more talking nonsense.
所以“cut the crap”就是别再抱怨、别再找借口或别再胡说八道。
Exactly.
完全正确。
And this is, this is common among teachers and well, parents.
这在老师和家长中很常见。
All right.
好了。
So cut the crap.
所以“别废话了”。
Now it's not very polite, right?
这不太礼貌，对吧？
So you wouldn't really say it to your boss or like a friend.
所以你不会对老板或朋友这么说。
Cut the crap is kind of rude and it's very spoken language.
"Cut the crap" 有点粗鲁，而且是非常口语化的表达。
So I wouldn't write it down and I would not use this with someone who is like a teacher.
所以我不会把它写下来，也不会对像老师这样的人使用。
Well, yeah, like an authority.
嗯，是的，比如权威人士。
You don't use it with them.
你不会对他们用这个词。
They might use it with you.
他们可能会对你用。
And for our last phrase, he said, whew, you had me going there for a while or you had
至于我们最后一个短语，他说，呼，你刚才让我紧张了一会儿，或者说你让我
me going there for a minute.
紧张了一小会儿。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a really interesting phrase.
所以这是一个非常有趣的短语。
We use this a lot in English, but it's not clear from listening to it what it might mean.
我们在英语中经常使用它，但光听的话不太清楚它可能是什么意思。
So you had me going there in this sense means, Oh, I was really nervous for a minute.
所以“you had me going there”在这个语境下意思是，哦，我刚才紧张了一会儿。
I really believed what you were saying.
我真的相信了你说的。
Exactly.
没错。
So maybe we could give an example, Marco.
所以也许我们可以举个例子，Marco。
All right.
好的。
Um, did you know that yesterday I won the lottery?
嗯，你知道吗，我昨天中了彩票？
I mean, I won like a million dollars and I had the perfect numbers.
我是说，我赢了一百万美元，而且号码全对。
Oh my God.
哦，天哪。
Really?
真的吗？
Can I have a million dollars?
能给我一百万美元吗？
I would love to help you out, man.
我很想帮你，兄弟。
But uh, yeah, no, I didn't actually win a million dollars.
但是，呃，不，我其实没赢一百万美元。
You had me going there for a minute.
你刚才让我紧张了一会儿。
You actually did for a little while.
你确实让我信了一小会儿。
You believed me.
你相信我了。
Okay.
好的。
Maybe not.
也许没有。
He's not that gullible.
他没那么容易上当。
All right.
好吧。
But that, that's what it means, right?
但这就是它的意思，对吧？
To believe someone's story or to think that, um, something's going to happen even though
相信某人的故事，或者认为某件事会发生，尽管
it doesn't.
它并没有发生。
You had me going there.
你让我紧张了一会儿。
That means what you thought was going to happen, didn't happen.
意思是你以为会发生的事，并没有发生。
So you can use it in the third person is like, yeah, I was telling him this awesome story
所以你也可以用在第三人称，比如，是啊，我给他讲了个很棒的故事，
and I really had him going for a while.
我确实让他信了一会儿。
He really believed me.
他真的相信我了。
And then I told him it wasn't true.
然后我告诉他那不是真的。
Okay.
好的。
Great phrases.
很棒的短语。
Well, that's it for today's episode of the podcast.
好了，这就是今天播客节目的全部内容。
We hope you enjoyed it.
希望你们喜欢。
If you did, please like, share, and subscribe.
如果喜欢，请点赞、分享和订阅。
Thanks for watching.
感谢观看。
We'll see you next time.
我们下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
We're never done, Amy, you've got an entire life ahead of me.
我们还没完呢，Amy，你还有整整一辈子要过。
Adventures waiting.
冒险在等着呢。
I can't settle down yet.
我还不能安定下来。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
It wasn't more than a month ago that you were rambling on about how you are tired of living
就在不到一个月前，你还喋喋不休地说你厌倦了单身生活，
the life of a Bachelor and how you envy your friends that have a family.
还羡慕那些有家庭的朋友。
I know.
我知道。
Let's think this through.
让我们好好想想。
First of all, you cannot leave Amy at the altar.
首先，你不能在婚礼上丢下Amy。
Not only will she be humiliated and kill you, but she's the woman that you love and the
她不仅会感到羞辱然后杀了你，而且她是你爱的女人，
woman of your dreams.
是你梦中的女人。
Why would you want to end that or jeopardize it like this?
你为什么要这样结束或冒险呢？
Second of all, you were just getting cold feet.
其次，你只是临阵退缩了。
You know deep down inside that you'd want to marry her.
你内心深处知道你想娶她。
So cut the crap and do it.
所以别废话了，去做吧。
You're right.
你说得对。
I'm being crazy.
我真是疯了。
Okay, I'm ready.
好了，我准备好了。
Let's do this.
我们开始吧。
Great.
太好了。
Phew.
呼。
That was a close one.
真是险啊。
You had me going there for a minute.
你刚才让我紧张了一会儿。
I thought I was going to have to slap some sense into you.
我还以为我得扇你几巴掌让你清醒呢。
Alright, so this is a popular scenario, right?
好了，这是一个很常见的场景，对吧？
Everybody on their wedding day, they get cold feet and they back out.
每个人在婚礼当天都会临阵退缩，然后打退堂鼓。
TV, movies, books, everyone loves this situation.
电视、电影、书，大家都喜欢这种情节。
Have you ever actually heard of or experienced or maybe known of somebody who actually left
你有没有听说过、经历过或者认识谁真的在婚礼上
the bride at the altar or the groom at the altar?
丢下新娘或新郎？
I don't know anyone who did that.
我不认识这样做的人。
Luckily, I think it's really sad.
幸运的是，我觉得这真的很可悲。
Yeah, me neither.
是啊，我也不认识。
I don't think it's really that common.
我觉得这并不常见。
No, but there was a movie just about this.
不，但有一部电影就是讲这个的。
So there's a woman, Julia Roberts, who tries and tries and tries to get married but never
有一个女人，朱莉娅·罗伯茨，她一次又一次地尝试结婚，但总是
can so it's called Runaway Bride because every time she goes to the altar, she gets nervous.
不行，所以电影叫《逃跑的新娘》，因为她每次走到圣坛前都会紧张。
She gets cold feet and she runs away.
她临阵退缩，然后逃跑了。
They call her the Runaway Bride.
他们叫她逃跑的新娘。
I can't imagine this actually happening to someone.
我无法想象这种事真的发生在某人身上。
I mean, you have all your family there, your friends.
我是说，你所有的家人都在那里，你的朋友。
I know.
我知道。
It'd be so embarrassing.
那会非常尴尬。
It's amazing.
真是不可思议。
And expensive.
而且很贵。
Exactly, because you've already paid for everything.
没错，因为你已经付了所有钱。
So do you get to eat the cake if you're the one who's left behind?
所以如果你是那个被留下的人，你能吃蛋糕吗？
I think so.
我觉得可以。
Everything's paid for, right?
所有东西都付过钱了，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
And drink all the liquor.
还能喝光所有的酒。
Alright, so that's all the time we have for today.
好了，今天的时间就到这里。
If you have any questions, any comments, you can come to our website at EnglishPod.com
如果你有任何问题或意见，可以访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
and we'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里等你。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Thanks for watching Life with Eli.
感谢收看《与伊莱一起生活》。